Gail Hobbs

gbhobbs97@gmail.com | (650) 290-3960 | San Francisco, California - **open to relocation** GitHub | LinkedIn | Plum Profile | Personal Website

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Developer adept at innovation with proficiency in React, Python, SQL, Azure. 2+ years of technical experience with object-oriented design, web and API development, and data analysis with Agile teams, with a specific emphasis on sustainability initiatives. Excited to bring my passion for building elegant, artful applications to a software team where I can create tools that improve communities, advance organizational objectives, and spark creative engagement.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Python • JavaScript • TypeScript • HTML5 • CSS • C# • C / C++ • Java • R • Matlab

Frameworks React • Redux • Recoil • Flask • Node.js

Databases SQL Server • PostgreSQL • SQLite • Power BI • Excel

Libraries SQLAlchemy • jQuery • AJAX • pandas • PyTest • Selenium • TensorFlow • scikit-learn

EXPERIENCE

Frontend/React Developer Intern, GBCS Group

Remote • 5/2023 - 8/2023

- Enhanced, reviewed, and maintained code pertaining to the <u>GBCS Group website</u> and <u>Aukai</u> platform, handling marine fleet management (commercial ships and vessels) to support tracking of emission targets and repairs
- Collaborated in project management to oversee execution of project quality, cost, software maintenance, direction

IT Innovation Engineer, International Atomic Energy Agency

UN Office, Vienna, Austria • 9/2021 – 8/2022

- Led rapid prototyping + built proof-of-concepts with SaaS applications, tested feasibility/scalability of new technologies using React.js, .NET, SQL Server, SharePoint, Jupyter notebooks, CKAN (open source data management system) to advance clientele's innovation objectives
- Configured application workflows on Azure with CI/CD and managed frontend work on apps for timely product delivery
- Adapted responsive design as acting QA tester and debugger for mobile site developments
- Strengthened Power BI reporting and database management on SQL Server for emergency reporting services

Data Science Research Intern, Qualcomm Institute at UCSD

UC San Diego • 9/2019 - 3/2020

- Spearheaded research on machine learning model creation for impact measurement on NGO environmental initiatives
- Presented analytics with Python + TensorFlow + pandas to communicate data on gender-focused NGO solutions

Physics Data Analytics Research Intern, University of Copenhagen

Copenhagen, Denmark • 8/2018 – 12/2018

 Performed numerical/data analysis for projects in physics involving linear and nonlinear optimization, eigenvalue problems, partial differential equations, using Python/Matlab, in support of various research topics

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Cesium Development for IAEA Data Platform - Private Repo | Demo

Full-stack application developed for testing integration with International Atomic Energy Agency's data platform API.

- Created and integrated revamp of Marine Radioactivity Information System (MARIS) using IAEA data API and Cesium
- Implemented functionality for viewing platform-connected data on top of additional marine layer data with React + CKAN for data queries, deployment and YAML pipeline via Azure

Audiofeel - GitHub | Demo

Full-stack React + Recoil + Flask application acting as an audio visual journal, storing audio visualizers with Al-generated color mood board

- Built Flask API for storing user account information + journal entries + visualizers
- Integrated ChatGPT, Meyda.js and Three.js libraries for audio analyzer and 3D graphics

Temperature Anomalies Visualizer - GitHub | Demo

GUI app for visualizing + animating 2°×2° grid temperature anomalies on country capitals with NASA data, 1880-2023.

• Mastered QT and Folium-Leaflet library in two days time in order to utilize GUI and map tools in application

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Bootcamp, Flatiron School, May 2023

Mathematics-Scientific Computation, Bachelor of Science, BS, University of California, San Diego, June 2020